

Ariel Triana

SOFTWARE DEVELOPER

+34-648-423-893

usich37@gmail.com

November 1st, 1999

Madrid, Spain

Software developer specialized Python with experience in handling large amount of data & ETL process design. Committed and passionate professional, with experience working in teams of 2-4 developers. Able to learn new technologies and platforms. I like to add value to any place I work, not only with my code but also with my personality focused on excellence.

Skills

- Software engineering: good practices, clean code, development cycle, agile methodologies
- Data structures and algorithms
- Artificial intelligence
- ETL pipeline MySQL, SQL Server, SQLite Github, Git Python, PHP, C#

- Teamwork
- Oral communication

Education

MATCOM, University of Havana, Cuba Bachelor of Computer Science | 09/2018 - 12/2022

Language

Spanish

English

Native Complete professional

competition

Experience

Python developer

BNZSA powered by Anteriad | January 2023 - present

- API creation using the FastAPI library for exposing company data to other internal services.
- Creation of ETL data processes to populate the databases for further processing using Artificial Intelligence and Data Science and Data Analysis techniques, using Pandas and Numpy.
- Creation of API using Codeigniter (PHP framework) to save
- Integration of the company's CRM with emailing campaigns in Adobe Marketo Engage.
- Automated emailing using Python and HTML with the Jinja2 template engine.
- Configuration and deployment of Python scripts in Apache Airflow
- Creation of Artificial Intelligence models for the identification and extraction of characteristics of the data-points in the database, using Sklearn and Tensorflow.
- Creation of event-oriented platform for integration projects with Adobe Marketo Engage.
- Creation of databases using MySQL.

Web developer

Cafeccino | April 2022 - December 2022

- Development and implementation of the database in SQL Server, and the link layer of the application with the database using EntityFramework.
- Development and implementation of user authentication and authorization on the platform using Identity.
- Development and implementation of the graphical interface using Angular JS.

Python back-end developer

INACV, Cuba | January 2022 - Novemeber 2022

- Developer of a measurement system for diabetic foot ulcers using computer vision.
- Development of a segmentation algorithm for RGB-D images obtained from the Intel Realsense D435i using Tensorflow and neural networks such as UNet.
- Implementation of a 3D reconstruction algorithm using computer vision techniques and the Open3D and OpenCV
- Implementation of a contrast enhancement algorithm and an ulcer detector using Artificial Intelligence.

Python back-end developer

ROAR (University of Havana) | February 2022 - May 2022

- Development and implementation of a publication and user recommendation system in a distributed social network, using NeuMF and Tensorflow.
- Development and implementation of the database using
- Deployment of application instances using Docker containers.

Python back-end developer

BattleSim (University of Havana) | September 2021 - January 2022

- Development and implementation of a genetic algorithm for the creation of height maps for simulation using the Perlin noise generation algorithm as a base.
- Python-like grammar domain-specific language implementation
- Implementation of a console application for the interaction with the simulator.



Ariel Triana

SOFTWARE DEVELOPER

+34-648-423-893

usich37@gmail.com

November 1st, 1999

Madrid, Spain

Software developer specialized Python with experience in handling large amount of data & ETL process design. Committed and passionate professional, with experience working in teams of 2-4 developers. Able to learn new technologies and platforms. I like to add value to any place I work, not only with my code but also with my personality focused on excellence.

Skills

- Software engineering: good practices, clean code, development cycle, agile methodologies
- Data structures and algorithms
- Artificial intelligence
- ETL pipeline MySQL, SQL Server, SQLite Github, Git Python, PHP, C#

- Teamwork
- Oral communication

Education

MATCOM, University of Havana, Cuba

Bachelor of Computer Science | 09/2018 - 12/2022

Language

Spanish

English

Native Complete professional

competition

Web developer

ReTex (University of Havana) | September 2021 - December 2021

- Implementation of a document search engine using free text aueries.
- Implementation of the vector model using word embeddings.
- Implementation of the data pipeline to integrate new documents into the system.
- Implementation of the visual interface using Vue JS with a look similar to Google.
- Implementation of an API to communicate the back-end of the system with the visual using FastAPI.

Web developer

Leira Web Solutions | June 2020 - January 2021

- Development and implementation of the company's website using PHP, MySQL and Jquery with Bootstrap.
- Development of web pages for clients using Wordpress as CMS.

Database Administrator - Front-end Developer

Yu-Gi-Oh Tournaments (University of Havana) | 2020

- · Implementation of the database model in MySQL
- Implementation of the data layer in the application using the Diango ORM
- Implementation of the visual interface using Bootstrap and Jauery

Research Projects

3D reconstruction of diabetic foot ulcers using Intel Realsense D435i depth cameras

INACV, Cuba | 2022

Numerical resolution of differential equations using Neural **Networks, Stochastic Gradient Descent and Multilayer** Perceptron

University of Havana, Cuba | 2019 - 2020

Awards

Best diploma thesis of the Bachelor's degree in Computer Science

University of Havana, Cuba | December 2022

Thesis: 3D reconstruction of diabetic foot ulcers using Intel Realsense D435i depth cameras

Mention in the Applied Mathematics jury

I Festival of Mathematics and Computing | 2020

Project: Numerical resolution of differential equations using Neural Networks, Stochastic Gradient Descent and Multilayer Perceptron

Mention in the Applied Mathematics jury

EMNO 2020 | 2020

Project: Numerical resolution of differential equations using Neural Networks, Stochastic Gradient Descent and Multilayer Perceptron